# Rohan Sahni

Panchkula, HR | +91-9992520053 | rohansworkid@gmail.com Linkedin | Github | Website

#### **SUMMARY**

Content Developer with about 2+ years of experience in teaching and developing programming courses in Scratch, Python, Django, Machine Learning, and Data Science to school and college students. Designed and developed over 10+ applications in the STEM domain.

#### **EDUCATION**

Department of Physics, Panjab University -

B. Sc-M.Sc Integrated Program(Physics) - Didn't complete.

2014-2019

#### **SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: Python, R, HTML/CSS, JS
- Database: MySQL, MongoDB
- Tools: Git/GitHub/MATLAB
- Frameworks/Libraries/Environments/APIs: Django, Flask, Bootstrap, T5 Transformer, and other basic ML modules.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Byju's - Think and Learn Pvt Ltd.

Job Roles:

- Curriculum Developer(1 Year): Scratch | Python | App Script
   | JavaScript | Django | Flask
- Developed coding curriculums and other internal software for Byju's Future School.
- Build JavaScript-based Math games for Byju's Math App.

Bangalore | June, 2021 - Till Date

#### **RoboGenius Innovation Studio**

Gurgaon | June, 2019 - June, 2021

#### Job Roles:

- Coding Masters Faculty & Research Assistant (1 Year): Python | HTML/CSS/Bootstrap Django |
  GoogleAPIs | Machine Learning | Arduino(TinyML) | CoppeliaSim Tensorflow(Beginner)
- Jr. Trainer (9 Months): LEGO Robotics | STEM Learning | 3D-Printing

#### Volunteer Work

- Volunteer at LIGO-India Education and Public Outreach Project (1 week)
- Intern at Center for Research in Applied Cognitive Sciences (2 Months)

# Papers Published & other works

- Interaction between Artificial Intelligence and Mechanical Engineering (3 Months): 2020 IJRAR,
   Volume 7, Issue 4 October 2020
- Review of Artificial Intelligence Driven Chemistry (3 Months): IJRASET Volume 7 Issue X, Oct 2019 doi: http://doi.org/10.22214/ijraset.2019.10011
- Review of Artificial Intelligence in Electrical Engineering (4 Months): IJSRD | Vol. 7, Issue 09, 2019
   ISSN (online): 2321-0613
- Invision Labs by RODINcode (3 Months): Django | Firebase | JavaScript
- ChatBot (4 Months): Web Scraping | RASA-X | NLTK(Python)
- CueMath(1 month): Python Instructor

### SIDE HUSSLES

Started <u>rodincode.github.io</u> for providing a free space for to help students learn to code by working on real data in the world.

# Classification of signals using CNNs - M.Sc Project

Chandigarh | Jan, 2019 - May, 2019

• Reviewed a method proposed by Kaschuee on PhysioNet's MIT-BIH Dataset and then compared its accuracy on arrhythmia classification using different optimizers.

# **COVID-19 Interactive Visualization with MANIM**

Chandigarh | May 2020 - Feb 2021

• Made a dashboard-like environment to make videos of graphs explaining how four different compartments of the SEIR Model (Susceptible, Exposed, Infected, and Recovered) for coronavirus spread changed with the time in a state/country.